[
    {
        "question": "What is the main folder on a storage device ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Platform"
            },
            {
                "option": "Interface"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Root Directory"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Home page"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Root Directory",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ram is ___ and ___.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "volatile, temporary"
            },
            {
                "option": "nonvolatile, permanent"
            },
            {               
                "option": "nonvolatile, temporary"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "volatile, permanent"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"volatile, temporary",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is not an item of a hardware ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "An mp3 file"
            },
            {
                "option": "A keyboard"
            },
            {               
                "option": "A monitor"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "A mouse"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"An mp3 file",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "A box that contains the central electronic compnents of the computer is the __",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "motherboard"
            },
            {
                "option": "system unit"
            },
            {               
                "option": "peripheral"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "input device"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"motherboard",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of device is computer monitor ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Input"
            },
            {
                "option": "Output"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Processing"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Software"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Output",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many options does a binary choice offer",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "one"
            },
            {
                "option": "two"
            },
            {               
                "option": "three"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "It depends on the amount available memory space available"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"two",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which menu is selected to cut, copy, and paste ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "File"
            },
            {
                "option": "Edit"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Tools"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Table"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Edit",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Storage device, inside the computer is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "CDROM"
            },
            {
                "option": "Zip Disk"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Super Disk"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Hard Disk"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Hard Disk",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ___ indicates how much data a particular storage medium can hold .",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "access"
            },
            {
                "option": "capacity"
            },
            {               
                "option": "memory"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "storage"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"capacity",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "If you are going to a site you use often, instead of having to type in the address every time, you should ___",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "save it as a file"
            },
            {
                "option": "make a copy of it"
            },
            {               
                "option": "bookmark it"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "delete it"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"bookmark it",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The quickest and easiest way in Word, to locate a particular word or phrase in document is to use the ____ command.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Replace"
            },
            {
                "option": "Find"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Lookup"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Search"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Search",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Oneor more defects or problems that prevent the software from working as intended or working at all is_",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "bug"
            },
            {
                "option": "bot"
            },
            {               
                "option": "programming language"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "fuzzy logic"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"bug",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "_______ is the part of the computer that does the arithmetical calculation.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Memory"
            },
            {
                "option": "OS"
            },
            {               
                "option": "CPU"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "ALU"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"ALU",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "A _____ can make it easier to play games",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "mouse"
            },
            {
                "option": "joystick"
            },
            {               
                "option": "keyboard"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "pen"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"joystick",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "File extensions are used in order to ______",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "name the file"
            },
            {
                "option": "ensure the filename is not lost"
            },
            {               
                "option": "identify the file"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "identify the file type"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"identify the file type",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Passwords enable users to_____",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "get into the system quickly"
            },
            {
                "option": "make efficient use of time"
            },
            {               
                "option": "retain confidentiality of files"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "simplify file stuctures"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"retain confidentiality of files",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "In page preview mode_____",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "You can see all pages of your document"
            },
            {
                "option": "You can only see the page you are currently working on"
            },
            {               
                "option": "You can only see pages that don't contain graphics"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "You can only see the title page of your document"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"You can only see the page you are currently working on",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "To navigate to a new Web page for which you know the URL, type that URL in the browser's _______ and press Enter.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Address bar"
            },
            {
                "option": "Domain bar"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Address button"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Name button"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Address bar",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The CPU, also called the _____ when talking about PCs, does the vast majority of the processesing for a computer",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "macro-processor"
            },
            {
                "option": "RAM"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Memory System"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "micro-processor"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"micro-processor",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "A computer's type, processor, and operating system defines its_____.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "brand"
            },
            {
                "option": "size"
            },
            {               
                "option": "speed"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "platform"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"speed",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The part of the CPU that accesses and decodes program instructions, and coordinates the flow of data among various system components is the ________",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "ALU"
            },
            {
                "option": "control unit"
            },
            {               
                "option": "megahurtz"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "motherboard"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"control unit",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Computer programs are writter in a high-level programming language; however, the human readable version of program is called____",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "cache"
            },
            {
                "option": "instruction set"
            },
            {               
                "option": "source code"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "word size"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"source code",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the difference between a CD-ROM and a CD-RW ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "They are the same, just two different terms used by different manufacturers"
            },
            {
                "option": "A CD-ROM can be written to and CD-RW can't"
            },
            {               
                "option": "A CD-RW can be written too, but a CD-ROM can only be read from"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "A CD-ROM holds more information than a CD-RW"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"A CD-RW can be written too, but a CD-ROM can only be read from",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term for how words will appear on a page ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "text-formatting"
            },
            {
                "option": "Character formatting"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Point size"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "typeface"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"text-formatting",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The simultaneous execution of two or more instructions is called _______",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "sequential access"
            },
            {
                "option": "reduced instruction set computing"
            },
            {               
                "option": "multiprocessing"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "disk mirroring"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"multiprocessing",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Multiprogramming systems______.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "are easier to develop than single programming systems"
            },
            {
                "option": "execute each job faster"
            },
            {               
                "option": "execute more jobs in the same time period"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "use only one large mainframe"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"execute more jobs in the same time period",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which device can understand difference between data and programs",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "input device"
            },
            {
                "option": "memory"
            },
            {               
                "option": "output device"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "microprocessor"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"microprocessor",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following devices have limitation that we can only read it but cannot erase or modify it?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "tape drive"
            },
            {
                "option": "hard disk"
            },
            {               
                "option": "compact disk"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "floppy disk"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"floppy disk",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not output device",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "plotter"
            },
            {
                "option": "printer"
            },
            {               
                "option": "monitor"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "touch screen"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"touch screen",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "A program written in a high level language is referred to as_______.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "source code"
            },
            {
                "option": "object code"
            },
            {               
                "option": "machine code"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "assembly code"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"object code",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "In order to save an existing document with a different name you need to ___",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "retype the document and give it a different name"
            },
            {
                "option": "use the save as command"
            },
            {               
                "option": "copy and paste the original document to new document and then save"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "use windows explorer to copy the document to a different location and then rename it"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"use the save as command",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The piece of hardware that converts your computer's digital signal to an analog signal that can travel over telephone lines is called a ______",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "red wire"
            },
            {
                "option": "blue wire"
            },
            {               
                "option": "tower"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "modem"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"modem",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following contains information about a single 'entity in the database - like a perosn, place, event, or thing'?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "query"
            },
            {
                "option": "form"
            },
            {               
                "option": "record"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "table"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"record",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the communications protocol that sets the standard used by every computer that accesses web-based information ?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "XML"
            },
            {
                "option": "DML"
            },
            {               
                "option": "HTTP"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "HTML"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"HTTP",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "A ______ is a computer attached to the internet that runs a special web server software and can send web pages out to other computers over the internet",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "web client"
            },
            {
                "option": "web system"
            },
            {               
                "option": "web page"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "web server"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"web server",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is a key function of a firewall?",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "Monitoring"
            },
            {
                "option": "Deleting"
            },
            {               
                "option": "Copying"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Moving"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Monitoring",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "The stantard protocol of the internet is ________",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "TCP/IP"
            },
            {
                "option": "Java"
            },
            {               
                "option": "HTML"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "Flask"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"TCP/IP",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "A program that generally has more user friendly interface than a DBMS is called a _____.",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "front end"
            },
            {
                "option": "repository"
            },
            {               
                "option": "back end"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "form"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"front end",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Coputers connected to LAN can ______",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "run faster"
            },
            {
                "option": "Share-information and/or share peripheral equipment"
            },
            {               
                "option": "email"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "go online"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"Share-information and/or share peripheral equipment",
        "tag" : "cs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Most web sites have a main page, the _____, which acts as a doorway to the rest of the web site page",
        "options":[
            {
                "option": "search engine"
            },
            {
                "option": "home page"
            },
            {               
                "option": "browser"
            },                  
            {
                "option": "URL"
            }
        ],
        "answer":"home page",
        "tag" : "cs"
    }
]



